<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/tag/personal/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2020-07-19T16:43:09+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/jasper2/tag/personal/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Sharvenium | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Writer, Programmer, Student</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">I started an Email Newsletter</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/newsletter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I started an Email Newsletter" />
      <published>2020-05-10T15:59:32+08:00</published>
      <updated>2020-05-10T15:59:32+08:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/jasper2/newsletter</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/newsletter/">&lt;p&gt;I have recently started my weekly email newsletter called “Sunday Stories” which you can sign up for and view previous issues &lt;a href=&quot;http://sharvenium.substack.com&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;
Through the email newsletter I want to be able to share useful insights and links to interesting content that I consumed that week. Although, I have tried implementing these into my blog posts, I feel that they would be more suited for an email newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you fancy receiving an email from me every Sunday and falling into a rabbit-hole of interesting links of blogs, journals, podcasts, twitter threads, books or newsletters, then sign up &lt;a href=&quot;http://sharvenium.substack.com&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay Epic,&lt;br /&gt;
Sharvenium&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Sharvenium</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="personal" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">I have recently started my weekly email newsletter called “Sunday Stories” which you can sign up for and view previous issues here. Through the email newsletter I want to be able to share useful insights and links to interesting content that I consumed that week. Although, I have tried implementing these into my blog posts, I feel that they would be more suited for an email newsletter.</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/computer-desk-electronics-indoors-374074-1870x1247.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Pandemic Prose #3</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/pandemic-prose-3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pandemic Prose #3" />
      <published>2020-04-18T21:40:26+08:00</published>
      <updated>2020-04-18T21:40:26+08:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/jasper2/pandemic-prose-3</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/pandemic-prose-3/">&lt;p&gt;Yes, I know it has only been a few days since the previous one but here I am again. I will now be structuring these newsletter-esque posts due to popular demand. By that I mean I suggested that as this blog has zero readers. I will start off my talking about why I don’t bother checking the daily stats anymore, followed by how I think this Pandemic will affect the future and lastly ending of with a personal touch by ranting about how screwed my quararoutine is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-i-dont-care-about-the-numbers-anymore&quot;&gt;Why I don’t care about the numbers anymore&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have stopped being obsessed with numbers because it clearly isn’t representative of the actual number of infections. Reports from Iceland have shown that when they tested a significant amount of the population, over 50% of those that tested positive for Covid-19 did not show any signs of symptoms at all. This is worrying. This combined with the 2 week transmission period for this virus means that the numbers we are seeing now were most likely the numbers we had 2 weeks ago. This number is also not inclusive of those who are not being tested. Hopefully the measures taken by different nations no matter how ineffective and pointless they are will help to slow down the number of infections and not strain medical systems around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-blur-at-the-end-of-the-tunnel&quot;&gt;The blur at the end of the tunnel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well experts have said that this virus could be spreading until we find a vaccine in 2021 which is worrying as this would affect all areas of life. This might mean that we would have to switch on and off lockdowns once cases start increasing again. This is deeply problematic as once we start to feel that the cases are minimal we would continue with life as normal albeit with better hygiene practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can lead to a second wave. All Pandemics in recent history have had a second wave. Think of the Spanish Flu or the H1N1 Influenza virus. The Spanish Flu experienced a second wave which was more deadly as the virus had mutated. The H1N1 Influenza had a second wave which was almost 5 times more deadly than the first both in terms of infections and deaths. Thus, we should brace ourselves mentally and physically for the inevitable second wave. Hopefully with modern technology, public awareness and exemplar leadership we can fight the second wave and come out stronger than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well what next? There can be a third wave or a fourth. Who knows but one thing is for certain. And that is that hopefully this virus can help as a human race to reflect on how our resources are being allocated, what hygiene practices we are maintaining etc. Hopefully there’s a light at the end of the tunnel but for now that remains a blur. We are living in a critical part of history and we can do our part no matter how small that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-quaranroutine-is-screwed&quot;&gt;My quaranroutine is screwed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes I fancy myself a bit of a poet who has ingenious word play. I read this &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://markmanson.net/newsletters&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; from author Mark Manson recently and it stuck with me. It made me realize how screwed my quaranroutine is. I wake up 10 minutes before my online classes begin at 7.50am . This is because they are unfortunately video calls for some lessons and I have to check in using a google form. However I believe that I can automate this process in a few day as the questions for morning reflections seem to be rotating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After quickly doing my morning businesses, I switch on my laptop with its sick desk set-up and then start my day. My breakfast and lunch is irregular as the breaks in our timetable are very weird. They are usually either in between breakfast and lunch or after noon. This leads to me eating whenever I have a free block of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spend the whole day in front of my computer taking the occasional break to flex my muscles by doing some push-ups which I learnt how to do quite recently. I have not left the house once in the past ten days and I have been going crazy with the lack of normalcy in my life. I finish my home-based learning in front of the computer at around 3. I then proceed to productively procrastinate on tasks and write articles such as this. Then I end my day at midnight to repeat the process the next day by waking up at 7.40am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really need to sort my life out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings me the end of this Pandemic Prose journal. Hopefully you are taking care and being sane staying indoors. You can tweet me at @sharvenium on twitter or send me a email at sharvenium@gmail.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay Epic,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sharvenium&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Sharvenium</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="personal" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Yes, I know it has only been a few days since the previous one but here I am again. I will now be structuring these newsletter-esque posts due to popular demand. By that I mean I suggested that as this blog has zero readers. I will start off my talking about why I don’t bother checking the daily stats anymore, followed by how I think this Pandemic will affect the future and lastly ending of with a personal touch by ranting about how screwed my quararoutine is.</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/img_0449.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Home Screens</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/home-screens/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Home Screens" />
      <published>2020-04-16T01:00:00+08:00</published>
      <updated>2020-04-16T01:00:00+08:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/jasper2/home-screens</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/home-screens/">&lt;p&gt;I have fallen into the world of iPhone home screen set-ups. Yes, this is different from my usual posts because I have more free time due to the current lockdown for Covid-19. I have fallen deep into the rabbit hole which is iPhone home screen set-ups. Yes, iPhones are not as customizable as Android phones where you can do anything you want natively. For iPhone it is not as simple but hey its fun messing around with different home screens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;finding-the-rabbit-hole&quot;&gt;Finding the rabbit hole&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arranging my home screen constantly isn’t something new for me. In fact I have been doing it ever since I first got my own phone at the young immature age of 12. I have used Android phones in the past and while they are extremely customizable, I did not enjoy the laggy user interface which made me jump the fence into the world of Apple. Critique all you want about how the iPhone is bad, but I personally loved the iPhone for every feature except for the customisability. I have tried jailbreaking in the past, however that was on a ancient iPhone 5 which was no longer in service. I did not want to risk the security of my daily driver so I just gave up. This was all good until I started listening to the Cortex Podcast hosted by CGP Grey and Myke Hurley where I discovered that they regularly nerd out about iPhone home screens. I thus decided to explore the world of apple shortcuts as can be seen in the exhibit below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-exhibit-of-sharveniums-home-screens&quot;&gt;The Exhibit of Sharvenium’s Home Screens&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/img_4338-231x500.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-966&quot; srcset=&quot;https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/img_4338-231x500.png 231w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/img_4338-139x300.png 139w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/img_4338-768x1662.png 768w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/img_4338-710x1536.png 710w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/img_4338-400x866.png 400w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/img_4338-800x1731.png 800w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/img_4338.png 828w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 231px) 100vw, 231px&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Specimen 1. The world of colorful icons made with Apple Shortcuts&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to use this wallpaper from heyeased.weebly.com so that I can hide the folders and the dock. The blank icons can be made using Apple shortcuts or using websites such as iempty.tooliphone.net . This home screen set-up was way too for a minimalistic user such as myself. Each colorful icon was made with blood, sweat and many many hours of browsing through r/iOSsetups and r/shortcuts on reddit. Each icon opened a menu list from which I could activate an app or open a web browser. I even modified a Covid-19 Tracker which would tell me detailed statistics when clicked. This was qutite fn to make and try to match the colors to that of a rainbow but it was too overwhelming for me. This made me explore other options such as the one below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/img_8562ba217819-1-231x500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-967&quot; srcset=&quot;https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/img_8562ba217819-1-231x500.jpg 231w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/img_8562ba217819-1-139x300.jpg 139w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/img_8562ba217819-1-768x1662.jpg 768w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/img_8562ba217819-1-710x1536.jpg 710w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/img_8562ba217819-1-400x866.jpg 400w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/img_8562ba217819-1-800x1731.jpg 800w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/img_8562ba217819-1.jpg 828w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 231px) 100vw, 231px&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Specimen 2. P E A K M I N I M A L I S M &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to use the same wallpaper from heyeased.weebly.com so that I can hide the folders and the dock. I decided to go the extra mile and also add blank icons inside my folder so that the apps (WhatsApp and Phone) can be in the center of the icon for symmetrical and aesthetic purposes. Well you might be wondering where all my apps are. They are in a folder in the top right with only a blank icon on the first page. This creates the illusion that there is nothing there as the folder cannot be seen due to this wallpaper and the icon is obviously blank so it also cannot be seen. Genius amirite. This is where I am currently at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe if there is a more significantly updated version it will be added below. Well that’s it for this out of the blue home screen post. Thanks Grey and Myke for pushing me down this rabbit hole. Do make sure to check the &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.relay.fm/cortex&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cortex Podcast&lt;/a&gt; if you want to nerd out about productivity, apple products, iOS apps, workspaces and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can contact me at Sharvenium@gmail.com or @sharvenium in twitter. Say Hi!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay epic,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sharvenium&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Sharvenium</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="personal" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">I have fallen into the world of iPhone home screen set-ups. Yes, this is different from my usual posts because I have more free time due to the current lockdown for Covid-19. I have fallen deep into the rabbit hole which is iPhone home screen set-ups. Yes, iPhones are not as customizable as Android phones where you can do anything you want natively. For iPhone it is not as simple but hey its fun messing around with different home screens.</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/img_31f81eaa7b5a-1.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Pandemic Prose #2</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/pandemicprose1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pandemic Prose #2" />
      <published>2020-04-15T14:29:55+08:00</published>
      <updated>2020-04-15T14:29:55+08:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/jasper2/pandemicprose1</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/pandemicprose1/">&lt;p&gt;We are living in history now. I have always wondered how it would feel like to live during a major historical event. I remember binge reading books about the middle-ages, plague and world wars since primary/middle school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was fascinated about how weird life must have been back then, one day you are having fun with your friends at school and then the next day you are stockpiling essentials and building a bunker to prepare for the war or getting enlisted into the military. How surreal must that have been. I remember reading about the Spanish flu and other illnesses such as the black plague and thinking “Wow how terrifying must that have been to hear through rumors about who has the illness and who has succumbed to the invisible enemy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now we are living through that nightmare. As mentioned in my previous pandemic prose post, I am pretty sure I heard ‘wuhan virus’ being mentioned in the news in early January. I ignored it then and thought that it was just some rare illness that a few unfortunate people have gotten. But that was not the case. It was spreading fast, exponentially. I started to notice more and more tweets in my feed about this new virus in the later half of January but once again scrolled through them to focus on the content and ideas that I wanted to consume on Twitter. This went on until one day my teacher talked about this virus and her experience in the SARS epidemic. Her stories about one of her students contracting the virus was pretty eye-opening and kept me awake that night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I fell into the rabbit hole of reading about this virus that originated in Wuhan, China and saw pictures of people eating bats which I do not recomend anyone to watch. This soon became worse when the first case on Singapore was confirmed on the 23rd of January. Paranoia sinked in and I became prettified and more hygienic on my morning commute than ever before. I then decided to calm myself using the stoic practice of weaving our own narrative. I told myself that since I am young and pretty healthy I won’t be that affected by this virus. Yes I know that I can spread to those around me so I also told myself that as my family and friends are all relatively young and healthy we won’t be that affected by this. This calmed me down but I still maintained my new hygiene practices because I knew that they are obviously good for me. This narrative continued but I decided be ‘alert not anxious’ until the virus spread to other countries outside of China&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I sit on my old office chair typing this on my amazing K380 keyboard listening to the sound of my obnoxiously loud ceiling fan writing this blog post on my iPad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has just been a crazy year. Hopefully you the probably first (and most likely last) reader to read this is living in a better time where the curve is flattened and the virus just magically disappears in the summer like what US President Donald Trump mentioned in a early press briefing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My life is pretty good right now compared to other less fortunate people who can’t work or attend online home-based learning lessons at home. I am fortunate to live in a pretty spacious bedroom where I have a sick desk set-up, iPad set-up and aircondition. I was actually looking forward to HBL (Home-Based Learning). I thought that it would be fun to listen to teachers talking about stuff on one half of my enourmous monitor while browsing the internet n the other half. But no. This is pretty depressing not talking to classmates or listening to funny jokes by the class joker. I would not consider myself an extroverted person but I still find siting at home by myself tiring and depressing because of the huge decrease in social contact. Humans are social beings whether you like to talk to everyone or hide in your shell 21 feet under the ground. This is pretty sad to have home-based learning. I muss school already and it hasn’t even been a full week yet. Enough of me ranting about how HBL and this virus sucks. We are all playing our part in one way or another and I guess this is one way I am playing my part in this pandemic. I woul rather have depressing HBL and be sad for a couple of weeks siting in my soulless room than have more people contract the virus and possibly even die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, I would be able to continue this Pandemic Prose. This was inspired by a Twitter post where I saw that people would look back on this crisis in a couple fo decades and think how life must have been. If you are in the future after this thing blows over, hi. Sorry for this messy article about this stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are in the present in the middle of all this, contact me at sharvenium@gmail.com or @sharvenium on twitter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.s Stay physically distant and may the odds be ever in your favour&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.p.s that sounded more dark than I meant it to be&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Sharvenium</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="personal" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">We are living in history now. I have always wondered how it would feel like to live during a major historical event. I remember binge reading books about the middle-ages, plague and world wars since primary/middle school.</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/img_0415-1870x1403.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Pandemic Prose #1</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/covid-19-march-reflection/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pandemic Prose #1" />
      <published>2020-03-31T17:08:56+08:00</published>
      <updated>2020-03-31T17:08:56+08:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/jasper2/covid-19-march-reflection</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/covid-19-march-reflection/">&lt;p&gt;Well Covid-19 has been spreading at a much faster rate now. Although numbers are irrelevant due to the limitations of testing kits, countries hiding numbers, number of mild carriers, number of asymptomatic and so much more. Here are today’s numbers (31st March 2020, 2AM EST)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confirmed Cases: 785,807&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confirmed Deaths: 37,820&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recovered: 165,659&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this can help you the reader to picture the situation that we all are in right now. Maybe you are thinking “Wow that was the peak and now we are so much better at controlling the spread”, or more likely “We were not prepared for the storm that was about to come…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-novel-corona-virus-chapter&quot;&gt;The Novel Corona Virus Chapter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been following the development of this virus since late-January ever since I heard of it from tech/investor twitter. People were panicking, buying more than necessary supplies and self-isolating themselves. I assumed that they were just overreacting and carried on with my life. Then this “Wuhan Novel-Corona Virus” news started to spread and soon my teachers were talking about their experiences of what was thought to be a similar epidemic in 2003, SARS AKA Severe Acute-Respiratory Syndrome. I went home that day and researched about this new unknown virus and SARS and saw it on the news that night. 💩 was getting real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to twitter and checked what was going on. Then I fell into the rabbit hole of watching videos about this. Hospitals in Wuhan were getting crowded, people were falling, Xenophobia against Chinese people was increasing, people were eating bats etc. My anxiety skyrocketed until I found out that this was similar to the Flu or so I thought&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-just-the-flu-chapter&quot;&gt;The “Just the Flu” Chapter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I liked this narrative as it was a way of convincing myself that this was not a big deal and that I did not need to be paranoid. (Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://sharvenium.com/the-stories-we-tell-ourselves/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; for a more detailed explanation on the stories we tell ourselves). The “Just the Flu” Chapter was the phase where I ignored the virus and all its news that closely because I believed that it was not going to be that severe due to the virus being more similar to the common cold than the previous similar epidemic (SARS). However, I still maintained a better standard of hygiene than usual ‘just in case’. Then the virus started to spread more rapidly and we soon learnt of how this virus was vastly different from previous Epidemics and Pandemics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-pandemic-chapter&quot;&gt;The Pandemic Chapter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we are in this Pandemic Chapter of this virus. Nations all around the world are going into lock down, implementing physical distancing, closing schools and implementing work from home policies to contain the spread of this virus. We have learnt that the virus has a fatality rate of around 5% with the elderly being the ones who are more severely impacted by this outbreak, children are not showing any symptoms although they have the virus, there are more asymptomatic carriers than previous estimates which call for lock downs and quarantines. Everyone is now alert and educated about this virus. Europe has become a hotspot for the pandemic with Italy, Spain and France having the highest amounts of deaths due to the corona virus. UK’s Prime Minister has tested positive after he told press that he was confidently shaking hands with corona virus patients and that herd immunity was the best way to control the spread. Now, the UK is under lock down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The global markets are crashing due to speculation and fears concerning the uncertainty of this new virus. US Companies are getting helped by the government to rise again with President Trump announcing the largest US Stimulus in history ($2,000,000,000,000).The bear market is probably going to exist for a while. (which has now turned back into a bull market due to the stimulus package). This is certainly a crazy time to be alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reflection&quot;&gt;Reflection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe we will look back at this Pandemic and think that the world has certainly gotten a lot better with work from home, online education, less pollution and better better hygiene practices. Perhaps this will spark the roaring 20s once again. Maybe this we will turn our world upside down . Whatever it may be we are living in the now. There’s no way I can predict the future sitting here on my cool 5 year old office chair, typing this on a wireless keyboard using my windows laptop with a flask of hot water nearby to prevent the phlegm from taking over my throat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can contact me @sharvenium on twitter or &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sharvenium@gmail.com&quot;&gt;sharvenium@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you : )&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Sharvenium</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="personal" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Well Covid-19 has been spreading at a much faster rate now. Although numbers are irrelevant due to the limitations of testing kits, countries hiding numbers, number of mild carriers, number of asymptomatic and so much more. Here are today’s numbers (31st March 2020, 2AM EST)</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/coronavirus-statistics-on-screen-3970330-1870x1246.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Magic</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/magic/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Magic" />
      <published>2020-01-25T10:07:31+08:00</published>
      <updated>2020-01-25T10:07:31+08:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/jasper2/magic</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/magic/">&lt;p&gt;This blog post is a bit different from the usual insanely original insightful productivity, life advice blog that I publish. I decided to write about a niche that I decided to dwell into recently. As the title suggests, it is about ‘Magic’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might have read about Magic in fantasy fiction books such as the extremely popular Harry Potter franchise or seen mind blowing videos about acts on America’s Got Talent of or Britain’s Got Talent in your recommended feed on YouTube. I used to watch these videos and be amazed before continuing on with my day. However, recently I decided to buy a pack of cards for a dollar and figure out what this whole ‘magic’ thing is.&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1551269901-5c5e14c25df7?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;amp;q=85&amp;amp;fm=jpg&amp;amp;crop=entropy&amp;amp;cs=srgb&quot; alt=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1551269901-5c5e14c25df7?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;amp;q=85&amp;amp;fm=jpg&amp;amp;crop=entropy&amp;amp;cs=srgb&quot; /&gt; &amp;lt;/figure&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;everything-is-an-illusion&quot;&gt;Everything is an illusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems like the audience member chosen is random but it may not be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems as though the magician had predicted what color crayon the judge would choose when in reality with a turn of the crayon box, all the crayons were now red.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems as if the person escaped from a death ‘trap’ when in reality the person hid in a tiny box underneath the trap and walked infront of the judges in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems as if the 10 year old who watched magic videos on YouTube is Albus Percival Wulfric Brian Dumbledore when he finds out your playing card after using the simple 27 card trick you can learn by watching a 5 minute YouTube video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;practice&quot;&gt;Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like any other cool hobby, you need to practice a lot if you want to suddenly make the card change or make a coin disappear. It took me about 2 hours to learn a cool pen swirling trick after watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TvytweSNkiE&quot;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; by Ali Abdaal. This is something that takes a lot of time. You can’t just learn how to make a coin disappear out of thin air after watching the relatively low barrier to entry videos about magic. You need to dedicate time to learning and practicing the craft to hone your skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently also on a pursuit to learn other ‘useless’ skills such as spinning a book, spinning a basketball, flipping my phone and so on. Similar to learning magic tricks which take hours to learn, these skills have tested my sanity and whether I can sit on my bed trying to spin my iPad for an hour while watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIRiWCPZoUyZDbydIqitHtQ&quot;&gt;Mike Boyd&lt;/a&gt; inspire me to learn other skills which I can live without.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-end&quot;&gt;The End&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings me to the end of this blog post where I share the basic idea of magic and the struggles of practicing consistently with a little bit of the ramble about me learning useless cool skills. If you are reading this, I apologize for the sub-par quality blog and I have linked some hopefully beneficial blogs written by me below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay Epic,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sharvenium&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;more-useful-blogs&quot;&gt;More useful blogs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sharvenium.com/content-consumption/&quot;&gt;Content Consumption&lt;/a&gt; – About the abundance of content in this digital age&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sharvenium.com/the-one-percent-rule/&quot;&gt;The One Percent Rule&lt;/a&gt; – About Growth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sharvenium.com/the-stories-we-tell-ourselves/&quot;&gt;The Stories We Tell Ourselves&lt;/a&gt; – Offers a different outlook on life&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Sharvenium</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="personal" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">This blog post is a bit different from the usual insanely original insightful productivity, life advice blog that I publish. I decided to write about a niche that I decided to dwell into recently. As the title suggests, it is about ‘Magic’.</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/harry-potter-book-and-black-headphones-with-trinket-1005012-1870x1247.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
