<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/tag/book-notes/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2020-07-19T16:43:09+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/jasper2/tag/book-notes/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Sharvenium | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Writer, Programmer, Student</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Book Review #5 – Outliers by Malcolm Gladwell</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/book-review-5-outliers-by-malcolm-gladwell/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Review #5 &amp;#8211; Outliers by Malcolm Gladwell" />
      <published>2020-05-24T14:22:53+08:00</published>
      <updated>2020-05-24T14:22:53+08:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/jasper2/book-review-5-outliers-by-malcolm-gladwell</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/book-review-5-outliers-by-malcolm-gladwell/">&lt;p&gt;I have seen Outliers by Malcolm Gladwell being quoted many times for its 10,000 hour rule to master a skill and I was intrigued. The Wikipedia description convinced me further. “In Outliers, Gladwell examines the factors that contribute to high levels of success”. As a self-help junkie, I jumped right on and finished this book in two days. I was going in with low expectations as I expected it to be a repetition of all the business books and biographies that I have read before. Like Shoe Dog by Phil Knight, Elon Musk by Ashlee Vance or Steve Jobs by Walter Isaacson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I was pleasantly surprised. As the title suggests, it talks about the things that is not written or only briefly mentioned in those books such as Bill Gates gaining unlimited access to a computer in his teenage years in the 1960s, The Beatles playing for over 10,000 hours in a club, Bill Joy having the opportunity to tinker with computers and more. These things are usually mentioned in a single sentence and are brushed off but Malcolm Gladwell explored them in detail and talks about how the experts in their fields practiced alot. This roughly adds up to 10,000 hours before someone becomes an expert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have seen this being quoted before with some people being huge believers of this principle while others think it is overrated and oversimplified. However, this book really cemented the idea that we all have our own advantages that we can leverage to be successful. No one starts off with nothing and gets everything. Everyone has something, the hard part is finding what that is and executing it. For me it may reading all these books and writing, for you it may be being really into agriculture. Leverage that opportunity and be the best agriculture blogger while working on your projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another idea that was mentioned in the book is the idea that there are golden ages for different groups of people at different times. Take for example the list of the 75 most wealthiest people in human history. Of those 14 were Americans born in the same period of the 1830s. These were people such as John D. Rockefeller (B. 1839), Andrew Carnegie (B. 1835), J.P. Morgan (B. 1837) etc. This was because in the 1860s and 70s, the American economy went through its biggest change. This was the time period when railroads were being built and Wall Street emerged and these people were lucky to have been in their prime then and take advantage of the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about an example closer to our current timeline. Bill Gates, Steve Jobs and Bill Joy were all born in 1954 and 1955 which allowed them to be ready for personal computer age in the 1970s. This with their experiences already dealing with computers allowed them to come ahead of the rest and become an outlier. Maybe it is a golden age now for remote businesses due to the 2020 Pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Malcolm Gladwell also talks about how one’s culture affects people using a variety of studies and examples. Although I do not agree with all of them, they are quite interesting and worth a read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the end of me spoiling this book for you. Read more articles about this and maybe even pick up this book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.sg/Outliers-Story-Success-Malcolm-Gladwell/dp/0316017930&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. You can find my Kindle Highlights below which might be useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;kindle-highlights&quot;&gt;Kindle Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biologists often talk about the “ecology” of an organism: the tallest oak in the forest is the tallest not just because it grew from the hardiest acorn; it is the tallest also because no other trees blocked its sunlight, the soil around it was deep and rich, no rabbit chewed through its bark as a sapling, and no lumberjack cut it down before it matured. We all know that successful people come from hardy seeds. But do we know enough about the sunlight that warmed them, the soil in which they put down the roots, and the rabbits and lumberjacks they were lucky enough to avoid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The emerging picture from such studies is that ten thousand hours of practice is required to achieve the level of mastery associated with being a world-class expertin anything,” writes the neurologist Daniel Levitin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Hudson is saying is that IQ is a lot like height in basketball. Does someone who is five foot six have a realistic chance of playing professional basketball. Not really. You need to be at least six foot or six one to play at that level, and, all things being equal, it’s probably better to be six two than six one, and better to be six three than six two. But past a certain point, height stops mattering so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“By no stretch of the imagination or of standards of genius,” Sorokin concluded, “is the ‘gifted group’ as a whole ‘gifted.’ ” By the time Terman came out with his fourth volume of Genetic Studies of Genius, the word “genius” had all but vanished. “We have seen,” Terman concluded, with more than a touch of disappointment, “that intellect and achievement are far from perfectly correlated.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The poorer children were, to her mind, often better behaved, less whiny, more creative in making use of their own time, and had a well-developed sense of independence. But in practical terms, concerted cultivation has enormous advantages. The heavily scheduled middleclass child is exposed to a constantly shifting set of experiences. She learns teamwork and how to cope in highly structured settings. She is taught how to interact comfortably with adults, and to speak up when she needs to. In Lareau’s words, the middle-class children learn a sense of “entitlement.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the Termites were into their adulthood, Terman looked at the records of 730 of the men and divided them into three groups. One hundred and fiftythe top 20 percentfell into what Terman called the A group. They were the true success stories, the starsthe lawyers and physicians and engineers and academics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, only one thing mattered: family background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here he was, a man with a one-in-a-million mind, and he had yet to have any impact on the world. He wasn’t holding forth at academic conferences. He wasn’t leading a graduate seminar at some prestigious university. He was living on a slightly tumbledown horse farm in northern Mis souri, sitting on the back porch in jeans and a cutoff Tshirt. He knew how it looked: it was the great paradox of Chris Langan’s genius.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those three things autonomy, complexity, and a connection between effort and rewardare, most people agree, the three qualities that work has to have if it is to be satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Success is not a random act. It arises out of a predictable and powerful set of circumstances and opportunities, and at this point, after examining the lives of Bill Joy and Bill Gates, pro hockey players and geniuses, and Joe Flom, the Janklows, and the Borgenichts, it shouldn’t be hard to figure out where the perfect lawyer comes from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cultures of honor tend to take root in highlands and other marginally fertile areas, such as Sicily or the mountainous Basque regions of Spain. If you live on some rocky moun tainside, the explanation goes, you can’t farm. You probably raise goats or sheep, and the kind of culture that grows up around being a herdsman is very different from the culture that grows up around growing crops. The survival of a farmer depends on the cooperation of others in the community. But a herdsman is off by himself. Farmers also don’t have to worry that their livelihood will be stolen in the night, because crops can’t easily be stolen unless, of course, a thief wants to go to the trouble of harvesting an entire field on his own. But a herdsman does have to worry. He’s under constant threat of ruin through the loss of his animals. So he has to be aggressive: he has to make it clear, through his words and deeds,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “culture of honor” hypothesis says that it matters where you’re from, not just in terms of where you grew up or where your parents grew up, but in terms of where your great-grandparents and great-great-grandparents grew up and even where your great-great-great-grandparents grew up. That is a strange and powerful fact. It’s just the beginning, though, because upon closer examination, cultural legacies turn out to be even stranger and more powerful than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chinese number words are remarkably brief. Most of them can be uttered in less than one-quarter of a second (for instance, 4 is “si” and 7 “qi”). Their English equivalents “four,” “seven” are longer: pronouncing them takes about one-third of a second. The memory gap between English and Chinese apparently is entirely due to this difference in length.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James Flynn, perhaps the world’s leading expert on IQ, has subsequently made a fascinating counterclaim. Asians’ IQs, he says, have historically been slightly lower than whites’ IQs, meaning that their dominance in math has been in spite of their IQ, not because of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No one who can rise before dawn three hundred sixty days a year fails to make his family rich.” Rise before dawn 360 days a year For the Kung leisurely gathering mongongo nuts, or the French peasant sleeping away the winter, or anyone else living in something other than the world of rice cultivation, that proverb would be unthinkable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill Gates was addicted to his computer as a child. So was Bill Joy. The Beatles put in thousands of hours of practice in Hamburg. Joe Flom ground away for years, perfecting the art of takeovers, before he got his chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wealthiest kids come back in September and their reading scores have jumped more than 15 points. The poorest kids come back from the holidays and their reading scores have dropped almost 4 points. Poor kids may out-learn rich kids during the school year. But during the summer, they fall far behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reading scores of the poor kids go up by .26 points. When it comes to reading skills, poor kids learn nothing when school is not in session. The reading scores of the rich kids, by contrast, go up by a whopping 52.49 points. Virtually all of the advantage that wealthy students have over poor students is the result of differences in the way privileged kids learn while they are not in school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KIPP&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything we have learned in Outliers says that success follows a predictable course. It is not the brightest who succeed. If it were, Chris Langan would be up there with Einstein. Nor is success simply the sum of the decisions and efforts we make on our own behalf. It is, rather, a gift. Outliers are those who have been given opportunities and who have had the strength and presence of mind to seize them. For hockey and soccer players born in January, it’s a better shot at making the all-star team. For the Beatles, it was Hamburg. For Bill Gates, the lucky break was being born at the right time and getting the gift of a computer terminal in junior high. Joe Flom and the founders of Wachtell, Lipton, Rosen and Katz got multiple breaks. They were born at the right time with the right parents and the right ethnicity, which allowed them to practice takeover law for twenty years before the rest of the legal world caught on. And what Korean Air did, when it finally turned its operations around, was give its pilots the opportunity to escape the constraints of their cultural legacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marita doesn’t need a brand-new school with acres of playing fields and gleaming facilities. She doesn’t need a laptop, a smaller class, a teacher with a PhD, or a big ger apartment. She doesn’t need a higher IQ or a mind as quick as Chris Langan’s. All those things would be nice, of course. But they miss the point. Marita just needed a chance. And look at the chance she was given! Someone brought a little bit of the rice paddy to the South Bronx and explained to her the miracle of meaningful work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not easy to be so honest about where we’re from. It would be simpler for my mother to portray her success as a straightforward triumph over victimhood, just as it would be simpler to look at Joe Flom and call him the greatest lawyer ever. Even though his individual achievements are so impossibly intertwined with his ethnicity, his generation, the particulars of the garment industry, and the peculiar biases of the downtown law firms. Bill Gates could accept the title of genius, and leave it at that. It takes no small degree of humility for him to look back on his life and say, “I was very lucky.” And he was. The Mothers’ Club of Lakeside Academy bought him a computer in 1968. It is impossible for a hockey player, or Bill Joy, or Robert Oppenheimer, or any other outlier for that matter, to look down from their lofty perch and say with truthfulness, “I did this, all by myself.” Superstar lawyers and math whizzes and software entrepreneurs appear at first blush to lie outside ordinary experience. But they don’t. They are products of history and community, of opportunity and legacy. Their success is not exceptional or mysterious. It is grounded in a web of advantages and inheritances, some deserved, some not, some earned, some just plain luckybut all critical to making them who they are. The outlier, in the end, is not an outlier at all.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Sharvenium</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="book notes" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">I have seen Outliers by Malcolm Gladwell being quoted many times for its 10,000 hour rule to master a skill and I was intrigued. The Wikipedia description convinced me further. “In Outliers, Gladwell examines the factors that contribute to high levels of success”. As a self-help junkie, I jumped right on and finished this book in two days. I was going in with low expectations as I expected it to be a repetition of all the business books and biographies that I have read before. Like Shoe Dog by Phil Knight, Elon Musk by Ashlee Vance or Steve Jobs by Walter Isaacson.</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/achievement-confident-free-freedom-69451-1870x1403.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Book Review #4 – TimeRiders Series by Alex Scarrow</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/book-review-4-timeriders-series-by-alex-scarrow/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Review #4 &amp;#8211; TimeRiders Series by Alex Scarrow" />
      <published>2020-05-08T09:43:56+08:00</published>
      <updated>2020-05-08T09:43:56+08:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/jasper2/book-review-4-timeriders-series-by-alex-scarrow</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/book-review-4-timeriders-series-by-alex-scarrow/">&lt;p&gt;Rating: 5/5
Recommendation: READ ALL NINE BOOKS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow. Just wow. I finished reading this book half an hour ago and I have been day dreaming since. It is that weird feeling you get after finishing a fiction book series. I have not felt this ever since I read the Harry Potter series back in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just felt lost. The realization hits about half an hour after finishing the book. I have a life to live. I have to catch up on overdue school work. It feels like I was completely removed from this world of Covid-19 news and people living their best lives on the internet. It feels weird. Now on to my non-spoiler review then a review filled with spoilers about me writing my thoughts about this series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first discovered the series when I was probably 11. My math teacher used to give away books that her son had read. Sometimes she would give to everyone in class while other times she used to only reward those who had done well in math tests. I used to routinely be rewarded with a few books. Once in her stack of books, I noticed that they all followed the same color scheme and had numbers on the side. It was a series. I took two books since each person was allowed to take a maximum of two. I took book 2 and 5. Yeah I know frustrating. I remember my fellow classmates who took the other books and we all traded the books after we had read ours. Yes back then when life was simple in the early single digits, people were all kind and friendly. So that is how I read Books 1,2,4 and 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While cleaning my bookshelf I stumbled upon this ancient relic of my past. The fifth book in the series. I recalled that I had not completely read all the books so I searched for the series on the internet. There it was. The complete list of all the books in the series. I decided to start somewhat chronologically with the third book. Then move on with the 6,7,8 and finally 9th book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hype&quot;&gt;Hype&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The series starts with the humble beginnings of the main characters. Liam O’Conner, Saleena Vikram and Maddy Carter. Liam should have died onboard the Titanic in 1911. Maddy should have died in a plane crash in 2010. Sal should have died in a fire in 2026. But they were saved a moment before death by a Time Traveler. The three of them were going to be apart of an agency to prevent greedy humans of the future from changing time because clearly things were always meant to happen in the same way right? Well then there’s a big plot twist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;spoiler&quot;&gt;SPOILER&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;”Spoiler.&lt;br /&gt;
”&lt;br /&gt;
”Seriously, spoiler. You have been warned do not scroll any further&lt;br /&gt;
”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok now for the spoiler review/thoughts. Holy smokes I cannot believe the story that Roald Waldstein told at the end. The agency was set-up because humans are living in a timeline that is repeating itself. Something like a simulation that people such as Elon Musk have pointed out based on the Fermi Paradox. It’s like a kid (humans) keeps on failing his final exams. So he has to retake his entire schooling so that he has a better chance of passing but he still fails due to being distracted with time travel. So the parents (the caretakers) keep on reseting the kid’s life so that he will eventually pass. It is like humans are the toddler intelligent species of the universe and we still haven’t learnt proper manners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing on, I did not really like the 8th book which was the Mayan Prophecy as Sal THE MAIN CHARACTER gets lost in the chaos space which was heartbreaking and I almost shed a tear when reading that. Another reason was because of Adam Lewis. The relationship between him and Maddy was just developing when Alex Scarrow decided to sacrifice him to save Maddy as some sort of heroic gesture. Not cool. You could have sacrificed literally any one of the hundred people who were there. Adam was my second favorite supporting character. After Rashim of course. The Mayan Prophecy was just pages filled with anxiety and despair with the occasion thrilling vibe when they were exploring the jungles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. My ‘review’ of the entire TimeRiders series. This is my second favorite fiction series of all time, with Harry Potter still holding the throne as its rightful owner. Be sure to tell me once you have read the book @sharvenium on twitter and sharvenium@gmail.com&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Sharvenium</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="book notes" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Rating: 5/5 Recommendation: READ ALL NINE BOOKS Intro Wow. Just wow. I finished reading this book half an hour ago and I have been day dreaming since. It is that weird feeling you get after finishing a fiction book series. I have not felt this ever since I read the Harry Potter series back in 2017.</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/beige-analog-gauge-697662-1-1870x1245.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Book Review #3 – Anything You Want by Derek Sivers</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/anything-you-want/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Review #3 &amp;#8211; Anything You Want by Derek Sivers" />
      <published>2020-01-17T19:08:12+08:00</published>
      <updated>2020-01-17T19:08:12+08:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/jasper2/anything-you-want</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/anything-you-want/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;thoughts-about-the-book&quot;&gt;Thoughts about the book&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far when I read books about a certain company or about how to start a business, it starts off as a story of a brilliant idea by the founder who later shared it with a group of friends in a small apartment or coffee shop, this idea later funded by the local billionaire or friend starts to grow rapidly and facing tons of problems before it eventually becomes a household name like Twitter, Amazon and Netflix. However this book was different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;review&quot;&gt;Review&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything You Want by Derek Sivers offers a fresh new take and outlook on the idea of a business. Instead of rambling about why you need investors and sell your business at the right time and stuff like that. Sivers suggests that you have a simple business model, start without any funding or investors, refuse formalities bravely, start executing ideas effectively, proudly exclude people, care about customers more, its okay to be causal, delegate work from the start and most importantly make it anything you want. This book helped me to change my perspective on the notion of starting a business and what its purpose is. So if you are interested in widening your perspective on business or you want to ‘grow’ your business, I highly recommend reading this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1535209039648-9524289505fd?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;amp;q=85&amp;amp;fm=jpg&amp;amp;crop=entropy&amp;amp;cs=srgb&quot; alt=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1535209039648-9524289505fd?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;amp;q=85&amp;amp;fm=jpg&amp;amp;crop=entropy&amp;amp;cs=srgb&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;summary--how-cdbaby-started&quot;&gt;Summary – How CDBaby Started&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-accidental-business&quot;&gt;The Accidental Business&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of the very motivating story of a broke 9-5 employee who wanted to make the world a better place and in the process make millions, Derek Sivers starts the book with the simple happy accident which led to him founding his multi-million dollar company. Derek Sivers, age 27, who had been working as a Professional musician for most of his adult life wanted to sell his CDs online in 1997. However, there were no business that would sell independent music online. When Sivers called up a big online record store, they said that the only way that he would be able to sell his music online was through a major distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a major roadblock for Sivers as getting a distribution label was hard in itself but they were notorious for paying musicians late and even kick musicians who didn’t sell well in the first few months. This led Sivers to think how hard could setting up his own online store be. After setting up a merchant credit card account and copying websites and templates from a few programming library books, Sivers had a ‘Buy Now’ button on his website. This was a big deal in 1997 and soon after a few friends of Sivers asked whether they too could sell their music on his website. This soon led to a couple more musicians wanting to sell their music on Derek Sivers website called &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdbaby.com&quot;&gt;CDBaby.com&lt;/a&gt; . When Sivers started spending more time on this website and adding more CDs, he soon realised that he had started a business and began to panic as he didn’t want to have a business because he was already doing what he loved which was being a musician. So he decided to make the business as small as he could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-907 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/1-us-bank-note-47344-1-300x212.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;426&quot; height=&quot;301&quot; srcset=&quot;https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/1-us-bank-note-47344-1-300x212.jpg 300w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/1-us-bank-note-47344-1-500x354.jpg 500w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/1-us-bank-note-47344-1-768x543.jpg 768w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/1-us-bank-note-47344-1-1536x1086.jpg 1536w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/1-us-bank-note-47344-1-2048x1448.jpg 2048w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/1-us-bank-note-47344-1-850x601.jpg 850w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 426px) 100vw, 426px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-business-model&quot;&gt;The Business Model&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However to start a business, you need to charge clients, so Sivers did the following…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Like most people, I had no idea what to charge for my service. So I went to the local record store in Woodstock, where they had some local musicians’ CDs on the counter. I asked the woman at the store, “How does it work if I sell my CD here?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;She said, “You set the selling price at whatever you want. We keep a flat $4 cut. And we pay you every week.” So I went home and wrote, on my new &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdbaby.com/&quot;&gt;cdbaby.com&lt;/a&gt; website, “You set the selling price at whatever you want. We keep a flat $4 cut. And we pay you every week.” I figured if it worked for her, it was fine for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Because it was taking me about forty-five minutes of work to add a new album to the site, I also had to charge $25 per album as compensation for my time. (Shows you how much I thought my time was worth in those days.) A few days later, I realized that $35 feels about the same as $25, so I bumped it up to $35 per album, which left me room to give discounts and still make a profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And that’s it! Six years and $10 million later, those same two numbers were the sole source of income for the company: a $35 setup fee per album and a $4 cut per CD sold. A business plan should never take more than a few hours of work. Hopefully no more than a few minutes. The best plans start simple. A quick glance and common sense should tell you if the numbers will work. The rest are details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings me to the end of spoiling this amazing book for you. You can find the link to the book and other related articles about this topic below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay Epic,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sharvenium&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;further-readings&quot;&gt;Further Readings&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Anything-You-Want-Lessons-Entrepreneur/dp/1511366079&quot;&gt;Anything You Want by Derek Sivers&lt;/a&gt; – The Book&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sivers.org&quot;&gt;sivers.org&lt;/a&gt; – Derek Sivers Blog Posts which are really unique and insightful&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Everything-Store-Jeff-Bezos-Amazon-ebook/dp/B00BWQW73E&quot;&gt;The Everything Store&lt;/a&gt; – The Story of Amazon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Hatching-Twitter-Story-Friendship-Betrayal/dp/1591847087&quot;&gt;Hatching Twitter&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q8knizONeXc&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt; – The Story of Twitter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Netflixed-Epic-Battle-Americas-Eyeballs/dp/1591846595&quot;&gt;Netflixed Book&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sr7kAEsJSK0&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt; – The Epic Story of Netflix&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Sharvenium</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="book notes" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Thoughts about the book So far when I read books about a certain company or about how to start a business, it starts off as a story of a brilliant idea by the founder who later shared it with a group of friends in a small apartment or coffee shop, this idea later funded by the local billionaire or friend starts to grow rapidly and facing tons of problems before it eventually becomes a household name like Twitter, Amazon and Netflix. However this book was different.</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/white-compact-disc-93388-1-300x200.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
