<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/tag/life-advice/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2020-07-19T16:43:09+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/jasper2/tag/life-advice/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Sharvenium | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Writer, Programmer, Student</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Journal</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/journal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Journal" />
      <published>2020-05-09T22:14:44+08:00</published>
      <updated>2020-05-09T22:14:44+08:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/jasper2/journal</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/journal/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;
    Nowadays everyone interested in productivity is looking for the next great note-taking app. Forget building a second brain in Notion or personal knowledge management system in Evernote. Roam Research is the cool kid on the playground. However, these apps are not future proof.
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    These applications might not be available in the next 30 or even 3 years. Let&amp;#8217;s say that you start building your second brain in Notion at the age of 12. Do you want to access these notes in the future? Of course you do. That is the main point of keeping a personal life wiki or second brain. You want to review these notes later on. Else you can just listen to that Tim Ferris podcast without diligently taking notes.
  
    To ensure that our note-taking app can be easily readable in 2050, we need to look back. What software has survived the past 20 years? (75 computer years) That will be usable in holographic displys 100 years from now. The answer?
  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    A plain text (.txt) file.
  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    You can create a plain text file and edit using notepad if you are on Windows and text edit if you are on MacOS. Just write the current date and start writing your thoughts. Then when you want to write the next day, just write the date at the top of the file and write your thoughts.
  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-998&quot; src=&quot;https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Capture-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;beast&quot; width=&quot;645&quot; height=&quot;490&quot; srcset=&quot;https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Capture-1.png 645w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Capture-1-300x228.png 300w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Capture-1-500x380.png 500w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Capture-1-400x304.png 400w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 645px) 100vw, 645px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    One of the benefits of a digital journal is that you can just ctrl+f and search away. Another way of using a journal is to create one text file for each topic that you have thoughts about. So for example my folder named &amp;#8220;thoughts on&amp;#8221; would have the files
  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      productivity
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      school
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      blogging
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      cats
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      memes
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      friends
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      internet
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    and in those files, I would write down the date and thoughts. Later on I can reflect on how my thoughts about something changed or became more concrete. The first best time to start a journal was 10 years ago, the second best time is now. (and other jokes we can tell ourselves. A day after I wrote this post, I switched to a completely new system. Blog/video coming soon.)
  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    This idea was inspired by Derek Siver&amp;#8217;s excellent post over at &lt;a href=&quot;http://sivers.org/dj&quot;&gt;sivers.org/dj&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Sharvenium</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="life advice" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Nowadays everyone interested in productivity is looking for the next great note-taking app. Forget building a second brain in Notion or personal knowledge management system in Evernote. Roam Research is the cool kid on the playground. However, these apps are not future proof.</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/white-printer-paper-2249432-1-1870x1244.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Friction</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/friction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Friction" />
      <published>2020-04-15T12:51:52+08:00</published>
      <updated>2020-04-15T12:51:52+08:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/jasper2/friction</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/friction/">&lt;p&gt;No this isn’t primary school and we are not learning about the magic that happens when you rub your hands together (It still is pretty cool though).
This article is about actual friction in real life which makes you less likely to do work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably have experienced it in your own life. When you kept your phone near your bed when sleeping at night, you open WhatsApp and Instagram first thing in the morning. When you have your iPad with YouTube on the first screen, you end up watching all of some cool new YouTuber’s video (I would suggest watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-rurif7Y01qNfH2-5N7ZzQ&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;mine&lt;/a&gt; *wink*). This is because it is so easy to do these stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you add friction to these actions like putting your phone at the other side of your bedroom or removing the YouTube application from your iPad you discover that you actually don’t bother walking all the way across the room just to catch up on social media or open YouTube the moment you open your iPad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friction can also be used to help you to do things at a higher frequency. I am writing this blog post now because of reduced friction. I started to use my ancient but trustworthy tank of a iPad Air 2 again for studying and creation purposes. I installed the wordpress app and boom here I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Publishing a blog post was previously a pain in the donkey because the WordPress admin website is laggy even with splendid internet connection and it takes a while for me to find my admin account details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this small change will help me write more blog posts. Removing and adding friction is a life-saver and try to implement it your life too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can contact me at @sharvenium on twitter. 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay Epic,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sharvenium&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Sharvenium</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="life advice" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">No this isn’t primary school and we are not learning about the magic that happens when you rub your hands together (It still is pretty cool though). This article is about actual friction in real life which makes you less likely to do work.</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/img_0412-1870x1249.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Hedonic Treadmill</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/hedonic-treadmill/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hedonic Treadmill" />
      <published>2020-02-16T13:03:57+08:00</published>
      <updated>2020-02-16T13:03:57+08:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/jasper2/hedonic-treadmill</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/hedonic-treadmill/">&lt;p&gt;You have probably had a moment in your life where you wanted to buy something that would without a doubt change your life for the better and that would allow you to be the next Elon Musk and bring you infinite amounts of joy like that $1000 Productivity Machine of a iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, What happened after you bought the iPhone? Did you become a productivity Ninja? Did that new iPhone make you more happy? Are you waking up everyday grateful you have an iPhone 11 Pro instead of a 2 year old iPhone X? The answer is most likely not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is due the &lt;strong&gt;hedonic treadmill&lt;/strong&gt; which is a process that reduces the impact of a major or minor life event as &lt;strong&gt;humans tend to quickly return to a relative stable level of happiness&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, when your pet unfortunately passes away, you might feel terrible and sad for the next couple of days, however after a couple of days you soon return back to your default level of happiness. It is due to this same reason that you probably do not feel happy every morning after a week of getting that new iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone  wp-image-934&quot; src=&quot;https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Capture-300x169.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;431&quot; height=&quot;243&quot; srcset=&quot;https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Capture-300x169.png 300w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Capture-500x282.png 500w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Capture-768x433.png 768w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Capture-400x225.png 400w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Capture-800x451.png 800w, https://sharvenium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Capture.png 887w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 431px) 100vw, 431px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing about the hedonic treadmill can help you to overcome bad situations such as failing your exam due to you knowing that your overall happiness will be normal again and that this is just a learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can also help you into justifying new purchases as you can remove the ‘infinite’ happiness benefit of getting that new iPhone and instead focus on other aspects such as that cool new camera which will help you to take great photos of your family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this short post about this hedonic treadmill can help you to value new purchases and deal with short term negative impacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay Epic,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sharvenium&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Sharvenium</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="life advice" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">You have probably had a moment in your life where you wanted to buy something that would without a doubt change your life for the better and that would allow you to be the next Elon Musk and bring you infinite amounts of joy like that $1000 Productivity Machine of a iPhone.</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/an-on-treadmill-1954524-1870x1247.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Reading Books</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/reading-books/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reading Books" />
      <published>2020-02-08T13:13:56+08:00</published>
      <updated>2020-02-08T13:13:56+08:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/jasper2/reading-books</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/reading-books/">&lt;p&gt;Most of the people you know probably used to read tons of books when they were around a decade old, devouring books like Harry Potter, Geronimo Stilton or some other fiction book. However, they &lt;strong&gt;used&lt;/strong&gt; to read. More and more people have lost touch with reading whether it is due to schools making reading a chore with the compulsory reading syllabus or the rise of social media, smartphone usage and other forms of content being more readily available than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-golden-age-of-consumption&quot;&gt;The Golden Age of Consumption&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not sure whether this is just a hasty generalization but most of the people around my age group (Teenagers) do not read books. They instead choose to indulge in other forms of content consumption such as watching YouTube videos, browsing TikTok and Instagram, watching Netflix and so on. This reduces the time available for other more meaningful and possibly life changing forms of content consumption such as listening to podcasts and audio books, watching online courses and documentaries, reading blog posts, newsletters and last but not least reading books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fiction-books-vs-tv-shows&quot;&gt;Fiction Books vs TV Shows&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people might argue that reading fiction books and watching TV shows are the same thing and I agree in some circumstances. When you are reading the Crazy Rich Asian Series or watching the Crazy Rich Asian movie, you are indulging in a form of entertainment. However there is a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While watching the movie might introduce you to the Crazy Rich Asian lifestyle and culture of Singapore, it is a form of passive entertainment where you are not thinking and instead just consuming the content. However, when you are reading the Crazy Rich Asian book, it is a form of active entertainment where are you using your brain and creativity to think of what the situation might look like and how the characters might have spoken in a certain tone or register of speech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading fiction books not only allow you to think creatively and take part in a form of active entertainment but it also has a small positive impact on social cognition which might seem very specific and random for me to write because it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When writing this blog post about reading fiction books, I recalled that a few days ago when I was listening to the Knowledge Project Podcast with Neil Pasricha &lt;s&gt;instead of scrolling through TikTok on the train&lt;/s&gt; Neil talked about how reading fiction every night before falling asleep and starting the day by reading fiction, can help you to have a small positive impact on social cognition (2018 Annual Review of Psychology).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;non-fiction-books&quot;&gt;Non-Fiction Books&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there is another side to this whole book world and that is the non-fiction world filled with towers of books about the lives of influential and important people in history, self-help books to increase your productivity and make you more mindful of the world around you instead of the screen you are using to read this and a whole lot more. I personally enjoy reading these types of self-help books and biographies as they introduce me to a whole new world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first book that really taught me anything about finance and investing was “Rich Dad, Poor Dad”. This book changed my whole perspective about money. I learned how the rich are getting richer and the poor are becoming more poor. This book might not have taught me how to start the next Facebook or become a real estate investor but it introduced me to the idea of having a business and having money work for me, not me working for money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, reading a self-help book is not all sun shines and daisies. Sometimes you might feel like the subject matter is not interesting or that it does not apply to you and that is absolutely fine. An example of this would be the 4-Hour Workweek by Tim Ferris which many people have claimed to be life changing.  However, I found the book quite boring as I felt that it was not applicable for me. Maybe it will change my life when I read it 5 years down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-you-start-reading&quot;&gt;How do you start reading?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pick up a book that you are interested in (Checkout Good Reads which is social media for books)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make it a Habit (e.g. listen to an audiobook while on the train or jogging)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Just DO it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings me to the end of this blog post/me rambling on about why reading is the &lt;strong&gt;best&lt;/strong&gt;. If you are interested in other cool articles about reading checkout the further readings below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay Epic,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sharvenium&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;further-readings&quot;&gt;Further readings&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sharvenium.com/hack-your-habits/&quot;&gt;Hack Your Habits&lt;/a&gt; – A blog post by me about habits&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Digital-Minimalism-Choosing-Focused-Noisy/dp/0525536515&quot;&gt;Digital Minimalism&lt;/a&gt; – A book by Cal Newport about minimizing technology to make time for stuff with higher priorities like reading&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Book-Thief-Markus-Zusak/dp/0375842209&quot;&gt;The Book Thief&lt;/a&gt; – One of my favorite historical fiction books about WW2&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Sharvenium</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="life advice" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Most of the people you know probably used to read tons of books when they were around a decade old, devouring books like Harry Potter, Geronimo Stilton or some other fiction book. However, they used to read. More and more people have lost touch with reading whether it is due to schools making reading a chore with the compulsory reading syllabus or the rise of social media, smartphone usage and other forms of content being more readily available than ever before.</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/blur-bookcase-books-bookshelf-298660-1870x1247.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">The One Percent Rule</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/the-one-percent-rule/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The One Percent Rule" />
      <published>2020-01-11T15:32:45+08:00</published>
      <updated>2020-01-11T15:32:45+08:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/jasper2/the-one-percent-rule</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/the-one-percent-rule/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The One Percent Rule&lt;/strong&gt; is something that I learnt when reading the book Atomic Habits by author James Clear. The One Percent Rule is when you start implementing healthy habits in your life that help to make each day at least one percent better. When you regularly do this, over the course of 3 months you can be &lt;strong&gt;‘twice as good as you were before’&lt;/strong&gt; and over the course of a year be &lt;strong&gt;365% better&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1534258936925-c58bed479fcb?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;amp;q=85&amp;amp;fm=jpg&amp;amp;crop=entropy&amp;amp;cs=srgb&quot; alt=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1534258936925-c58bed479fcb?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;amp;q=85&amp;amp;fm=jpg&amp;amp;crop=entropy&amp;amp;cs=srgb&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This idea is simple because of the compounding effect that habit building has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you start to workout, you realize that you need to drink more water to be healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+1%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you start drinking more water you realize that all that energy drinks and food takeaways you eat daily isn’t good for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+1%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leads you to sleep more and have a better quality sleep by reducing devices nearing bedtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+1%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you do not have your phone near your bed anymore, you decide to read a book on your kindle while dimming the lights half an hour before sleeping each day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+1%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leads you to…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably see where I am going with this idea. You don’t have to be twice as healthy as you were yesterday, all you need to be is 1% better over the course of a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also you will feel much better due to the lessened workload and stress you are putting on yourself while you are trying to improve one percent instead of 100%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1505739616034-1fbcb08941a2?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;amp;q=85&amp;amp;fm=jpg&amp;amp;crop=entropy&amp;amp;cs=srgb&quot; alt=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1505739616034-1fbcb08941a2?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;amp;q=85&amp;amp;fm=jpg&amp;amp;crop=entropy&amp;amp;cs=srgb&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe try this today, start by doing something small that will have a compounding effect like making your bed every morning or by exercising daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings me to the end of this relatively short blog post. I have linked some relevant and useful links about this topic below which are more in depth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay Epic,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sharvenium&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-readings&quot;&gt;Further Readings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Atomic-Habits-Proven-Build-Break/dp/0735211299&quot;&gt;Atomic Habits&lt;/a&gt; – Book about Habits by James Clear (I highly recommend that you read this)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesclear.com/the-1-percent-rule&quot;&gt;The One Percent Rule&lt;/a&gt; – A blog post by James Clear&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bfLHTLQZ5nc&quot;&gt;The Two Day Rule&lt;/a&gt; – A YouTube video about how to make habits consistent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sharvenium.com/hack-your-habits/&quot;&gt;Hack Your Habits&lt;/a&gt; – A blog post by me about how to hack your habits&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Sharvenium</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="life advice" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">The One Percent Rule is something that I learnt when reading the book Atomic Habits by author James Clear. The One Percent Rule is when you start implementing healthy habits in your life that help to make each day at least one percent better. When you regularly do this, over the course of 3 months you can be ‘twice as good as you were before’ and over the course of a year be 365% better.</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/jasper2/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/adventure-cold-daylight-fog-291732-300x201.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
